Guide to the Stephen Henry Schneider Papers SC1053
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Climatic Change Editorial Records, Accession ARCH-2015-078
  - 98:3-4, 2010 Feb (Box 28, Folder 1-17)
  - 99:1-2, 2010 Mar (Box 29, Folder 1-14)
  - 99:3-4, 2010 Apr (Box 30, Folder 1-14)
  - 100:1-2, 2010 May (Box 31, Folder 1-7)
  - 100:3-4, 2010 Jun (Box 32, Folder 1-19)
  - 101:1-2, 2010 Jul (Box 33, Folder 1-11)
  - 101:3-4, 2010 Aug (Box 34, Folder 1-11)
  - 102:1-2, 2010 Sep (Box 35, Folder 1-15)
  - 102:3-4, 2010 Oct (Box 36, Folder 1-13)
  - 103:1-2, 2010 Nov (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - 103:3-4, 2010 Dec (Box 38, Folder 1-13)
  - 104:1-2, 2011 Jan (Box 39, Folder 1-17)
  - 104:3-4, 2011 Feb (Box 40, Folder 1-13)
  - 105:1-2, 2011 Mar (Box 41, Folder 1-18)
  - 105:3-4, 2011 Apr (Box 42, Folder 1-12)
  - 106:1-2, 2011 May (Box 43, Folder 1-11)
  - 106:3-4, 2011 Jun (Box 44, Folder 1-17)
  - 107:3-4, 2011 Aug (Box 45, Folder 1-17)
  - 108:1-2, 2011 Sep (Box 46, Folder 1-20)
  - 108:3-4, 2011 Oct (Box 47, Folder 1-10)
  - 109:1-4, 2011 Dec (Box 48, Folder 1-16)
  - 109:3-4, 2011 Nov-Dec (Box 49, Folder 1-13)
  - 110:1-2, 2012 Jan (Box 50, Folder 1-20)
  - 110:3-4, 2012 Feb (Box 51, Folder 1-17)
  - 111:1, 2012 Mar (Box 52, Folder 1-11)
  - 111:2-4, 2012 Mar-Apr (Box 53, Folder 1-19)
  - 112:2-4, 2012 May (Box 54, Folder 1-18)
  - 113:2-4, 2012 Jul-Aug (Box 55, Folder 1-15)
  - 109:1; 113:1; 114:1, 2011 Dec; 2012 Jul; 2012 Sep (Box 56, Folder 1-17)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2015-078
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2015-162
  - Whole Earth Systems symposium materials (papers and DVD/DAT), 2005 Feb 10-12 (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2016-005
  - SHS 2 Heartland Chicago-anti SHS comments; SHS memorial; Terry Root Interview (External Hard Drive), circa 2010-2011; 1.2; 1 hard drive(s) (external) (Box 1)
  - SHS Film Numerous Interviews: Erlich, Field, Edwards, etc.; Steve 1979 interviews; 2009 on Anecdotes, Birthday, etc.; COP 15; SHS Symposium Boulder; San Diego (External Hard Drive), circa 2009-2010; 1.1; 1 hard drive(s) (external) (Box 1)
  - Schneider tape 1, undated; 1.3; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - Schneider tape 3, undated; 1.4; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - Schneider tape 4 (day 2/3), undated; 1.5; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - Scnheider tape 5, undated; 1.6; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - Schneider tape 6 (Day 3 + Roast), undated; 1.7; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - Climate Warrior (transcript), 2011-06-06 (Box 1)
  - Whole Earth Systems: Science, Technology and Policy Symposium, 2005-02-10-2005-02-12
    The Whole Earth Systems symposium is an international gathering of academic, government, media, and non-profit scholars and leaders who have accepted the challenge of an interdisciplinary approach to environmental concerns... We celebrate the professional contributions of Stephen Schneider whose career-thus-far has personally and intellectually touched all of these fields of inquiry.
    The Stanford symposium was organized into several major themes, such as preserving whole Earth systems, economics and policy analysis, and "media-rology"—the role of scientists as communicators and advocates. Because the conference represented a wide spectrum of expertise, speakers and panelists often used broad brushstrokes to make their point. For example, Stanford economist Kenneth J. Arrow offered a concise history of global sustainability predictions, from Adam Smith to the present, then raised the question of whether the modern world is sustainable.
    The symposium was sponsored by CESP; the Energy Modeling Forum; the Stanford Institute for the Environment; the New-Land Foundation; the Ju Tang Chu and Wu Ping Chu Foundation; the Climate, Community and Biodiversity Alliance; and anonymous donors.
  - Climate Warrior
- Additional Climatic Change Editorial Records, Accession ARCH-2016-030
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2016-098
  - Birth Certificate, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Divorce, circa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - BIO 15N, 2005-2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brockman, Inc. - Publishing, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - IPCC Geneva, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SHS Memorial Symposium, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Thomas Reuters - Highly Cited Researcher Award, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Wildlife Federation - Conservation Achievement Award, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Book publishing correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - California Hall of Fame, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - White House Visit, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Climatic Change Editorial Records, Accession ARCH-2016-098
  - Reviews and Correspondence, circa 1988-1995 (Box 2)